SEAN STICKLAND

Software Engineer

021-829-780 • EMAIL • LINKEDIN • GITHUB • PORTFOLIO

ABOUT ME

I'm an early career software engineer with 9 years previous experience as an IT Support Specialist. I am a graduate of Dev Academy, a rigorous TypeScript-based coding bootcamp, where I was recognized by the lead teacher as "one of our most advanced students".

To upskill further, I'm currently finishing off a course on Python and AWS infrastructure run by AWS and Unitec, called <u>AWS re/Start.</u>

Combining my extensive industry experience in the IT world, with my enthusiasm and aptitude for software development and cloud computing, I'm eager to join a high-performing development team where I can contribute my skills and continue to learn.

SKILLS & EXPERTISE

- Experienced with TypeScript, Node.js, React, Redux, Python, HTML, CSS, Tailwind, SQL
- Skilled with Git, GitHub, code reviews, and RESTful APIs.
- Currently finishing course on AWS Lambda, S3, EC2, RDS and other AWS services
- Deployed applications using Docker, and Microsoft Azure.
- Have written extensive unit tests using Jest and other testing libraries.
- Proactive about asking questions, admitting when I don't know something, and finding answers on my own.
- Developed automation scripts in Batch, PowerShell, and Azure Process Automation to streamline IT tasks and increase efficiency.

EXPERIENCE

Part Time Work and Side Projects | May 2023 - Present

- Studying and building side projects while maintaining WordPress sites.
- Currently finishing <u>AWS re/Start</u>, a course that covers building AWS cloud infrastructure using Python.
- Created and deployed <u>Pictophone</u>, a Pictionary/Telephone hybrid online game.
- Created an online version of the American Trivia show Jeopardy!

Dev Academy | Jan 2023 - May 2023 |

Student

- Coached and mentored students who came to the course with less experience.
- Made projects in React and Express, while also focusing on human skills like providing feedback, collaboration, and working in agile teams.
- Led a team of 5 in creating a <u>restaurant ordering app</u>, where I took responsibility for coding the back-end and much of the front-end UX/UI design.

Tekne LTD | Dec 2020 - Dec 2022 |

IT Support Specialist

 Tekne is a small managed service provider, coordinating the IT needs of several small businesses, which fostered a greater sense of individual ownership over challenges and a wider spectrum of tasks to tackle.

- Using Azure Process Automation, I automated the offboarding of leaving employees, saving hours a week, and preventing disgruntled employee incidents.
- Developed strong organizational and communication skills needed to effectively schedule and manage the IT needs of several businesses across NZ.
- Collaborated with team members and clients to solve complex IT challenges, which further developed problem-solving skills and built strong relationships.
- Showed the ability to rapidly adapt to new clients, environments, and systems.

Vista Entertainment | Apr 2019 - Nov 2020 |

ICT Technician

- Vista is a large SAAS company headquartered in Auckland.
- Stayed up to date with industry trends and best practices to improve system performance and security, effectively managing risks.
- Wrote Batch and PowerShell automation scripts to expedite computer setup processes.
- Collaborated with developers to resolve routine hardware and software issues, further developing my technical and problem-solving skills.

Sony Mobile, Oceania | Feb 2015 - Dec 2018 |

Service Warranty & Training Manager

 Managed staff training, repairs, refunds, and dealt with tribunal cases against Sony.

Sony Electronics, Oceania | Oct 2013 - May 2015 |

Customer Support Representative, IT Specialist

• Customer facing consumer support for VAIO laptops.

EDUCATION

2024 - AWS re/Start

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner

2023 - Dev Academy Aotearoa

• Certificate in Applied Software Development

2010 - Auckland University of Technology

• Certificate in Computer & Mathematical Sciences

ACHIEVEMENTS

During my graduation ceremony at Dev Academy, my teacher specifically called out my aptitude for programming and leadership.

PERSONAL

In my spare time, I enjoy playing D&D, guitar, pub quizzes, karaoke, and watching terrible action movies. I like teaching, learning, and making people laugh.

REFERENCES

See below from Dev Academy. Others available upon request.

Level 5, 12 Morgan Street Level 2, 275 Cuba Street Auckland 1011 Wellington 6011

28 July 2023

To Sean's future employers,

Sean attended and successfully completed the Dev Academy Bootcamp at the Auckland campus in 2023.

As a Lead teacher, I taught and worked closely with Sean throughout this time and I regarded him as one of our most advanced students. He applied himself to every challenge and did so with curiosity.

He seemed to have a natural talent for programming and I was always impressed with the quality of his work. He tended to research his approach well and deliver features in a timely manner. He would also consider proper functionality as well as edge-cases. For example, he delivered server-side API code using database returning arrays to improve performance. This was something he discovered himself.

Sean was an ambitious and reliable teammate among his peers and the quality of their final project reflected his influence. This included presentations which he delivered with confidence.

I appreciated his straight-forward communication style, especially when it came to giving and receiving feedback. Lastly, I enjoyed his sometimes twisted sense of humour.

I recommend Sean as a well-rounded, talented developer and wish him success in his career and chosen craft.

Sincerely,

Alex Coaton (Lead Teacher)

devacademy.co.nz

